本字幕由 PTT同志影视作品板 2013重新校稿
原字幕取自网路资源  仅供学习 禁用任何商业盈利行为
校稿：zetaxedc、mohiwa
同志亦凡人 Queer As Folk S01E17
这是我们在凯旋门前
Mmm, here we are in front of the arc de triomphe.
这是圣心堂
And here we are in front of the sacre-coeur.
这是拿破仑公墓前
And here we are in front of Napoleon's tomb.
他已经死了  真幸运
Lucky him. He's dead.
这是我正在把玩..
Here I am playing...
法式面包条  就像是
a loaf of french bread, like a...
你们能不能收敛点？
Would you two cut it out?
妈  你打断我了
Ma, you're interrupting.
我讨厌情侣们在你面前亲热
Well, I hate it when couples make out in front of you.
这是法国啊  我们这是法式热吻
It's French. We're Frenching.
拍完这张照片
And with that,
大卫和迈克就告别了巴黎
David and Michael bid adieu to paris.
「Fin」
Fin.
「Fin」  就是「结束」的意思
Fin. That means the end.
「Bon」  是「很好」的意思
Bon. That means good.
希望大家没觉得太无聊
Well, I hope everyone wasn't too bored.
开玩笑吧？
Are you kidding?
自从《甘地》之後我还没这麽开心
I haven't been that entertained since "Gandhi".
噢  真是一生难忘的绝妙旅行
Oh, it just looked like the trip of a lifetime.
的确像是一生那麽漫长
It sure felt that long.
巴黎最让人难忘的
The thing you have to remember about Paris
不是在卢卡斯·卡尔通用餐
is not dining at Lucas-Carton,
也不是在圣苏尔比斯购物
or shopping on the Rue de St-sulpice.
而是一些小事
It's the little things.
比如  分享一根长条法式面包
You know, sharing a baguette
漫步在塞纳河边
while strolling Sur La Seine...
塞什麽  亲爱的
The sur le what, honey?
-塞纳  妈妈           -那是条河
-The seine, mother.   -It's a river.
-谢谢你  宝贝   -嗯哼
- Thanks, baby. - Mm-hmm.
谁想来点...红酒？
Would anyone like some, uh,vin rouge?
露茜  你不会觉得
Lucy, you wouldn't know the difference
红酒和漱口水有什麽区别的
between vin rouge and Listerine.
好了  我只想知道
Okay, all I want to know is,
你们见到凯瑟琳·德纳芙了吗 (影星)
Did you meet Catherine Deneuve?
天啊  我爱死她了
Oh, god, I love her.
没有  但我们在凡尔赛见到了
No, but we did meet this wonderful couple
一对夫妇
in Versailles.
我猜猜  是路易斯和玛丽 (法国王室)
Oh, let me guess, Louis and Marie?
不  是让·皮埃尔和伊维特  (球星影星)
No, Jean-Pierre and Yvette.
他们在十六大道有座豪宅
They have the most fabulous maison in the 16th.
噢  嚐嚐这白乳酪
Oh, try the brie.
-味道像精液       -天啊
-Tastes like cum. -Oh, jeez!...
切达乾酪在哪里
Where's the cheddar?
-嗨  一起聊聊吗           -行啊
-Hey, mind if I join you? -No.
嘿  宝贝
Hey, sweetie.
嗨
Hi!
哦  天哪  他长得可真快
Oh-ho-ho, god, he gets bigger every time I see him.
都归功於吉拉姆给他做的那些法国食物
It's all that delicious french baby food Guillaume makes him.
所以这个协议进行得如何？
So this, uh, arrangement's working out for you?
是啊  比我想的要好很多
Yeah, a lot better than I thought.
亲爱的  即使你不想听我这个…
Honey, even if you don't want to listen to me as...
很关心你的人所说的话
someone who cares about you,
你至少也得听听我的法律建议吧
I wish you'd at least take my legal advice.
事实上....  我们一星期之後就要结婚了
Actually... we're getting married a week from today.
他对你做了什麽  搞大你肚子吗
What'd he do? Knock you up?
不  他昨天收到了驱逐令
No, his deportation letter came yesterday.
所以我们得马上办理了
So we have to do it now.
也许迈克能在婚礼上帮我们录影
Maybe Michael can film the ceremony.
这得看起来像真的一样
It's got to look real,
以防听证会上需要用到
in case there's an evidentiary hearing.
我快要崩溃了
I am freaking out.
为何？因为她没请你当伴娘吗？
Why? Because she didn't ask you to be maid of honour?
你以为这很好笑吗？
You think this is funny?
他们就要结婚了  下星期
They're going through with it... Next week!
他们不是真的结婚
It's not like they're really getting married.
只是为了让他能留在这个国家
It's just so he can stay in the country.
那麽  要是他不走了怎麽办
Now, what if he never leaves?
要是他就这麽一直留在这里怎麽办
What if he becomes a permanent fixture?
要是我的姨妈有蛋蛋怎麽办
What if my aunt had balls?
那他就是我舅舅了
She'd be my uncle.
现在都太迟了  都是我的错
Now it's too late. It's all my fault.
我们什麽都改变不了了
And there's not a goddamn thing we can do about it.
我要坐前座
Shotgun.
就不能让清洁阿姨收拾这些吗？
Can't we leave that for Magdelena?
我们可是付了薪水的
That is why we pay her.
你了解我的
You know me.
东西没收拾好我会睡不着
I can't sleep until everything's put away.
你真龟毛         (亦爱肛交)
You're so anal.
你可幸运了
Lucky for you. Hmm.
小心点  小心点
Careful, careful, careful!
天啊  你这是干嘛
Geez, what was that for?
你陪我度过了我一生中最美好的时光
Well, I don't believe I thanked you properly
我还没好好谢谢你呢
for showing me the best time of my life.
那我也该好好谢谢你
Well, I don't believe I thanked you either...
能让我陪着你
for letting me show you.
真不敢相信泰德竟然会睡着
Could you believe Ted snoring?
我还以为他在盖一间小木屋呢
I thought he was building a log cabin.
这些家伙根本不知道
Those guys have no idea
自由大道外面的世界有多精彩
that there is a world outside of Liberty Avenue.
上星期之前你也不相信啊
Well, you didn't either until last week.
这酒太棒了
This cab is great.
我要再订购一箱
I'm going to order a case of this
招待参议员巴克斯
and serve it for senator Baxter.
你觉得我该邀请他们吗？
Do you think I should've invited them?
谁
Who?
我妈妈  维克叔叔  还有大夥儿
My mom and Uncle Vic, and the guys.
我以为你不想邀请他们
I thought you didn't want to.
我以为你不想让我邀请他们
I thought you didn't want me to.
我说了没事的
I said it'd be fine,
只要布莱恩规规矩矩的就没问题
as long as Brian behaves himself.
你知道的  那些政治募捐者
Oh, you know, political fund-raisers,
我觉得他们不会喜欢同性恋的
I just don't think it's their thing.
巴克斯参议员很支持同性恋
Senator Baxter's very supportive of gay issues.
我觉得一点问题也没有
I would think that's everybody's thing.
但我不...  我不知道在我们那些朋友身边
Yeah, but I don't... I just didn't know if they'd be comfortable
他们会不会不自在  他可是个参议员
around our other friends, and a, a state senator.
那麽你做了正确的决定
Then you made the right decision.
所有社团都可以集会  只有我们的不行
Every club is allowed to meet, except ours.
这不公平
It's not fair.
这就是现实  小芙
Welcome to the real world, Daph.
没人会在乎一个「异同联盟」
Nobody gives a shit about a gay-straight alliance.
不是这样的  看看上次有多少人来了
That's not true. Look how many people came.
多少  八个吗
What, eight?
最後只留下了两个  我数了
And two left. I counted.
而且  他们只是为了免费安全套才来的
Besides, they only came 'cause we handed out condoms.
你能相信他现在的状态吗
Can you believe how he was carrying on?
"塞纳河"
"sur la seine."
我差点噎死
I nearly choked on my pate.
他只是有些轻飘飘
He's just dazzled.
让他在超市上几天班
Give him a couple of days back at le grand Mart,
他就会回到现实世界了
He'll come down to earth.
我不知道
I don't know.
自从他和大卫在一起
Ever since he's been with David,
他就像是变了一个人似的
it's like he's got this whole new life.
拜托  我们一起住了两年
Please, he was like, my roommate for two years.
现在我根本就见不到他
Now I never even see him.
我们还得求他一起去酒吧玩
We have to beg him to come out to the bars.
他都不回我电话了
He won't fucking return my calls.
天啊  看看这个
Oh, my god! Would you look at that?
是谁会开一辆金色的米亚达
Who would drive a gold Miata?
-敞着顶篷                       -在大冬天
- With the top down? - In winter?
你们喜欢这车吗
How do you like it?
这是你的吗
Oh, this is yours?
大卫送给我的
David got it for me.
他  他给你买了一辆车？
He-he bought you a fucking car?
看看车牌
Check out the plates.
星际队长
Captain Astro.
真可爱
That's cute.
你们觉得颜色怎麽样
What do you think of the colour?
我有点担心金色会太显眼了
I was worried that the gold might be a tad showy.
谁说不是呢
Oh, you wouldn't want that.
我今早给你打电话了
You know, I called you this morning.
但你没有回我电话
But, uh, you didn't call me back.
我一直很忙
Well, I've been really busy...
想和我们一起去健身房吗
Wanna go to the gym with us?
不行  我得去运动俱乐部找大卫
I can't, I'm meeting David at our sports club.
好吧  你今晚有安排吗
Well, what are you doing tonight?
咱们去伍迪吧玩吧
How about coming out to Woody's with us?
抱歉  我不能去
Sorry, no can do.
我们在法加诺预定了晚餐
We have reservations at Pappagano
和波波还有梅丽桑德一起
with Bobo and Melisande.
波波和梅丽桑德？
Bobo and Melisande?
听起来像是扮装皇后
Sounds like a couple of drag queens.
波波是个理专  我们请他帮忙投资
Um, Bobo is a broker. We have our investments with him.
「我们」
"Our".
嗨  宝贝
Hi, honey.
-是        -大卫  大卫
- It's...  - David. David.
是啊  不用担心  我已经拿到了
Yeah, don't worry. I-i just picked them up.
而且我已经和宴会承办人谈过了
And I already spoke to the caterer.
要办派对吗
Having a party?
不过是  几个大卫的朋友  吃个晚饭
It's just... It's just a couple of David's friends, for dinner.
好吧  我该走了
Well, um, I... I better get going.
再见
See you!
-再见      -拜拜
-Ta-ta. - Bye-bye.
再见
Ciao!
你觉得怎麽样
So, what do you think?
你像是从电影中走出来的
It's like a movie.
还是恐怖片
A horror movie.
吉拉姆还得把尺寸改改
Guillaume still has to fit it for me.
他很擅长针线活
He's great with a needle and thread.
他有什麽不擅长的吗
Is there anything he can't do?
赢得我朋友的喜爱
Charm my friends.
他有试图赢得我们的喜爱吗
You know, I-I didn't know he was trying.
噢  这不是可可·香奈尔吗
Oh, well if it isn't Coco Chanel.
有客人啊  太幸运了
Company. Aren't we lucky.
你觉得怎麽样
What do you think?
我还得再做些修改
It's going to take a lot of work, but...
不过做完之後你就会美若天仙的
you will be a vision by the time I'm through.
谢谢你  小纪
Thanks, Gui.
-我去看看      -是盖斯
-I'll get him. -There's Gus.
没关系  我去吧  他跟我很熟了
Oh, it's all right. He's used to me.
那新郎要穿什麽呢
So what is the groom going to be wearing?
一套很传统很保守的黑礼服
A very conservative, very traditional black tux.
我们不能掉以轻心  婚礼必须像是真的
We can't take any chances, it has to look real.
真是闹剧
This is a fucking farce.
你用不着发脾气吧
Hey, you don't have to lose your temper.
为什麽  你都发神经了
Why not? You've lost your mind.
我从没想过我会穿上婚纱
Well, I never thought I'd see myself in one of these.
虽然我得承认   三不五时
Although now and then, I must admit
我也幻想过成为新娘
I often dreamed of being a bride.
是真的
It's true.
我猜拉拉也免不了有这种幻想
I suppose even dykes can't escape that fantasy.
只是你嫁错人了
Only you're marrying the wrong person.
你从来没有向我求过婚
You never asked me.
我是说茉蕾妮
I mean Melanie.
我没搞错的话
Yeah, last time I checked,
我们是住匹兹堡
we lived in Pittsburgh
而不是佛蒙特州  (此洲允许同性恋结婚)
and not Vermont.
不管怎麽样  现在已经晚了
And anyway, it's too late.
茉儿和我已经完了
Mel and I are finished.
她可不这麽认为
She doesn't think so.
事实上  你是她全部的牵挂
In fact, all she thinks about is you.
她把一切的责任都归咎於自己
She blames herself, for everything.
那麽  她错了
Well, she's wrong.
因为都是我的错
Because it's me.
是我把她从我身边逼走的
'cause I pushed her away.
如果我还爱她  又怎会逼走她呢？
Why would you push away someone you love?
不好意思去了这麽久
Sorry for taking so long.
小家伙真调皮
He was being... very fussy.
那麽  我们是不是该看看礼服了？
Alors,shall we start on the gown?
好的  我要用别针别住这儿
Okay, I just want to pin... here.
一切都被毁坏了  我的画  我的书
Everything was destroyed. My drawings, my books.
你知道是谁干的？
You know who did it?
我猜得到  克里斯·赫伯
I can guess. Chris Hobbs.
我说我们去揍死他
I say we go and beat the shit out of him.
嘿  我们应该提出些建设性的意见
Hey, we're trying to be constructive here.
我觉得我的提议就很有建设性
I thought I was.
你告诉校长了吗
Did you tell the principal?
他才不会管呢
He doesn't care.
都是因为我们组织的那个小团体
It's all because of this group.
什麽小团体
What group?
贾斯汀和达芙妮建立了一个
Justin and Daphne started
「异同学生联盟」
The gay-straight student alliance.
但被他们叫停了
Yeah, but they shut us down.
理由是我们不是正当管道创立的
Said we didn't go through the proper channels.
就算你按照规定来  结果也还是一样的
Even if you had, it probably wouldn't have made any difference.
你非得向这孩子泼冷水吗
Do you have to piss on the kid's idealism?
知道这些社会现实对他有好处
He might as well know the truth.
我们只是希望有一个交流的地方
We just wanted a place to talk.
可是连那样也不行
We couldn't even have that.
鉴於现在发生的事
Well, considering what's happened,
或许你不应该
Maybe it's best that you don't...
把自己弄得那麽高调
draw attention to yourself.
你想让我躲躲藏藏的吗
You want me to hide?
我只是希望你能够安全
I want you to be safe.
那我就该直接屈服吗
So I should just give in.
一辈子都受他们的恐吓
Let them intimidate me my entire life.
你要坚持做自己  亲爱的
You stick up for yourself, sunshine.
而你  要坚定地支持他
And you stand beside him.
黛比  你能不能别管这事
Debbie, would you please stay out of this?
我忘了
I forgot.
他只是在我这吃饭睡觉打手枪而已
He just eats, sleeps and jerks off here.
我还是管住我的大嘴巴好了
I'll keep my big mouth shut.
妈  这不仅仅是为了我
Mom, this isn't about me,
也不是因为学校里发生的那些事
or even what happened at school.
这是为了喊出同志的心声
This is about speaking out.
同志应该被了解  不管人们是否愿意倾听
Demanding to be heard, whether people want to hear you or not.
你这些话是从哪儿学来的？
Where'd you learn all that?
你和老爸以前这麽教我的
It's what you and dad taught me.
是吗
We did?
反正圣詹姆斯学院是不可能教他这些的
Well, he sure as hell didn't learn it at the St. James academy.
那麽  你们晚餐吃的怎麽样
So, how was dinner with, uh...
波波  还有  梅丽桑地
Bobo and... Melisand?
是梅丽桑德
Melisande.
梅丽桑德非常幽默  而波波
Melisande's a hoot. And Bobo's like,
则是我见过的最聪明的人
the smartest person I have ever met.
你  你会喜欢他们的
You... You'd love them.
你能不能不要靠在那上面
Um, could you not lean on that?
我刚擦完那块儿
I just got done polishing it.
对不起
Sorry.
你为什麽都没有
So why haven't you introduced any of your...
把你的新朋友介绍给你的老朋友认识一下
new best friends to any of your old best friends?
没有时间啊
Well, who's had the time?
我们刚从巴黎回来
You know, we just got back from Paris.
你去了巴黎吗  天啊  我都没听说
You went to Paris? God, I hadn't heard.
滚开一点
Fuck off.
是啊   你正希望如此吧
Yeah, maybe you'd like that.
什麽
What?
反正你现在有了全新的上流生活
Now that you've got this fabulous new life...
屁话
That's bullshit.
是吗
Is it?
你漏了一个污点
You missed a spot.
我认识你多久了
How long have I known you?
差不多快一辈子了吧
Like, forever?
我可不认为这是屁话
I don't think it's bullshit.
你可以让一下吗
Could you move, please?
旅行啊  衣服啊  车啊
The trip and the clothes and the car.
都很无趣
They're boring.
你也很无趣
You're boring.
无趣
Boring?
我倒觉得我变成了一个很有趣的人
Well, I happen to think I've become a very interesting person.
你他妈的现在纯粹就是个跟屁虫
You've become a fucking little snot.
为什麽  就因为我终於拥有了自己的生活吗
Why? 'cause I finally have a life?
谁的生活  你的吗？
Whose life? Yours?...
还是他的？
Or his?
贾斯汀告诉我在过去的几个月里
Justin tells me that over the past couple of months
他遭遇了人身攻击  骚扰  以及辱骂
He's been physically attacked, harassed, called names,
而学校却没有采取任何措施予以制止
and nothing has been done to stop it.
泰勒夫人  我向你保证  如果我知道的话
Well, Mrs. Taylor, I can assure you that had I known about it,
我是绝对不会允许这种情况发生的
I would never have tolerated such behaviour.
他还说他试图建立一个社团
Well, he also said that he tried to start a club
目的是为了跨性取向的人们交流
for gay and straight students,
而你却禁止他们集会
and you refused to allow them to meet.
正如我们一个老师向贾斯汀解释的那样
As one of the teachers already explained to Justin,
他  社团的建立没有通过正当的管道
He... He didn't go through the proper channels.
所谓正当的管道是指什麽呢
And what are the proper channels?
首先  他必须得到学校校董会的认可
Well, first he would have to get approval from the school board,
而我正是校董会的领导者
of which I am the head.
然後他用来集会的教室也必须得到批准
And then he would have to seek approval for a meeting room,
找一个教职员工做指导
find a faculty advisor,
这些步骤贾斯汀都没有遵守
None of which Justin bothered to do.
我敢保证  如果他知道这些程序的话
Well, I'm sure he would've bothered,
他一定会遵守的
had he known.
那麽.. 申请表呢？
So... Where are the forms?
我们现在就可以填
We can fill them out right now.
泰勒夫人  你也知道
Mrs. Taylor, as you know,
圣詹姆斯是所私立学校
St. James is a private academy.
我们不能随便任凭一切毫无节制
We are not required to make allowances for everyone and everything.
这也正是家长们把孩子送进来的原因
That's why parents send their children to this school,
就是为了这里良好的环境
for the special environment.
以及一流的教育水平
And for the superior education,
贾斯汀如果肯用心  一样可以享受这些
which Justin is getting, when he puts his mind to it.
这跟我的异同联盟社团有什麽关系？
What does this have to do with having a gay-straight alliance?
好吧  如果我允许你建立这个社团
All right, suppose I gave you permission to organize your club.
马上另外一个学生跑过来跟我说
And then another student came to me
要建一个「白人至上」的俱乐部
and asked to start a club for, say, White supremacists.
我是不是也应该允许呢？
Should I allow that too?
不好意思  珀金斯博士
Excuse me, Dr. Perkins,
我觉得这个比喻很侮辱人
But I happen to find that analogy extremely offensive.
我们有些家长很迫切地期望自己子女与众不同
Some of our parents would be hard-pressed to see the distinction.
我则迫切希望看到我儿子被一视同仁
Well, I'm hard-pressed to see the similarity.
不是每个人都能像你那样
Not everyone is as accepting
坦然接受你儿子的性偏好
of your son's sexual preference as you are.
那不是偏好
It's not a preference.
我一开始也觉得难以接受
I was that way at first too.
这更说明了那些人需要学会理解
Which is why it's important that they learn.
泰勒夫人  学校还有更重要的东西要教
Mrs. Taylor, there are more important lessons to be taught here.
比宽容还重要？
Than tolerance?
有人在本地同志报上发现什麽大新闻了吗
Anyone seen a certain hot little item in our local gay rag?
我的广告还在刊登吗
Is my ad still running?
「只要你够大  我就坐得上去？」
"if you've got it, I'll sit on it"?
-这是你的广告词吗     -才不是咧
- Is that you?              - No.
我说的是  这个
I mean... this.
我觉得我从来没有从正面打开过这报纸
You know, I don't think I've ever opened this paper from the front.
「议员戴安·巴克斯的资金筹集会」
"Fundraiser for state senator Diane Baxter will be held
「将在大卫·卡梅隆医生和」
at the home of Dr. David Cameron and
「迈克·瓦特尼先生家举行」
Mr.Michael Novotny."
什麽  快让我看看
What? Let me see that.
嘿  我们点的餐好了吗
Hey, can we have our food?
先吃面包吧
Eat the bread.
噢  天啊
Oh, my god!
我儿子步入上流社会了
Oh, my baby's in high society.
现在我们的女主人一身光鲜地走进来了
Oh, and here's the hostess with the mostess.
你怎麽没有跟我说这事
Why didn't you tell me about this?
要招待一个参议员
Entertaining a senator!
天啊  你现在是一个社交女王了  小迈
God, you're a society lady now, Mikey.
你最好别向她展示你们在巴黎拍的照片
I hope you don't show her those slides from Paris.
这只不过是大卫办的一场小聚会而已
That's just a little thing that David's throwing.
我想他大概给她做过脊椎矫正
I think he gave the senator an adjustment once, or something.
我们点的东西还没有好吗
Could we please have our food?
这是沙拉   又不会变凉
It's salad. It's not going to get cold.
糟糕  穿什麽衣服见议员合适
Oh, shit! What do you wear to meet a senator?
我觉得我应该穿我那件
Oh, I think I'm going to wear my, um,
那件橘色西装  还有那条石灰绿的领带
my orange suit, and my new lime green tie.
彰显朴素的一面  这麽穿绝对没错
Oh, understated, yeah. That's definitely the way to go.
你打算穿什麽  布莱恩
How about you, Brian?
阿玛尼？  杰尼亚？  还是普拉达？
A little Armani? Zegna? Prada?
穿个屁
Nada.
我又没被邀请
I wasn't invited.
你当然被邀请了  我们都会被邀请的
Of course you're invited. We're all invited.
-是吧  宝贝          -那聚会非常无聊的
-Right, honey?  -Well, it's going to be really stuffy.
你知道的…无聊透顶
You know, no fun at all.
而且  你们还必须捐赠..
And you have to make a contribution...
那又怎样  能见议员一面多不容易
So? I mean, how often do you get to meet a senator?
你还得工作呢
Well, you have to work.
我可以请假啊
I'll take it off.
听着  这就不是你的场合  好吗？
Look, this just isn't your thing, okay?
所以别闹了
So just drop it.
现在可以给我一份外带火鸡肉卷吗？
Now can I please get the turkey meatloaf to go?
好的  宝贝
Okay, sweetie.
让我为那位先生上完餐
Uh, just let me serve this man his dinner.
我得去趟洗手间
I gotta go to the washroom.
所以  泰德  作为我的会计师
Say, Ted, as my accountant,
你觉得我花点「政治献金」的钱如何？
what do you think about increasing my political contributions?
我真应该再次感谢你  大卫
And I do have to thank you again, David,
让我们参观你美丽的家
for opening up your beautiful home to us.
我应该谢谢您才对  议员
Well, thank you, senator,
感谢您长期来支持同志权利的立法
for your ongoing commitment to progay legislation.
相信我  如果我能对此多尽点力
Oh, believe me, if I have anything to do with it,
而且我正打算全力以赴
and I intend to,
将来你和迈克就可以在这里举行婚礼了
you and Michael will be celebrating your wedding reception right here.
让我们为此乾一杯
Let's drink to that.
不好意思
Now if you'll excuse me,
我应该...做些例行公事
I should, um... do what I'm supposed to do at these affairs,
竭力争取些捐款
and drum up some donations.
-祝你好运     -谢谢
-Good luck.   -Thank you.
我们上次参加的派对  我们看了
The last party I was at, we watched
「我不管你们去年夏天干了些什麽」  (惊声尖叫)
"I don't give a shit what you did last summer"
配啤酒和玉米片
and ate beer and nachos.
现在你喝着香槟 吃着鱼子酱馅饼
Now you're drinking champagne eating caviar tarts
招待参议员
and entertaining a senator.
希望我们没来得太迟
I hope we're not too late.
我可不希望错过什麽
I'd hate to miss the crudities.
糟了
Oh, shit.
天哪  这像在守丧  谁死了？
Jesus. This looks like a wake. Who died?
你们来这里做什麽？
What are you doing here?
亲爱的  我们绝不会错过你们的宴会
Well, we wouldn't have missed your party for the world, sweetheart.
我想我们的邀请函寄丢了
Yeah, we figure our invitation got lost in the mail.
该死的邮政系统啊
Damn that postal service.
我要写给我的参议员投诉
I'm going to write my senator.
不用了  她就在这里
You don't have to. She's here.
这是私人慈善活动  你们不能就这样闯进来
This is a private benefit. You can't just break in.
「闯进来」吗？
"Break in"?
我们是你家人  又不是强盗
We're family, not bandits.
医生 这是一张小支票
Here's a little cheque, doc.
我想足够应付我们所有人的份了
I think it should be enough to cover all of us.
小迈  领带不错啊
Nice tie, Mikey.
借过一下
'scuse me.
要嚐个馅饼吗？
Care to try a tart?
-鸡尾酒呢？  -两三杯吧
-Cocktail?  - Or two or three.
大卫  真对不起
I'm so sorry, David.
我真的没想到他们会不请自来
I can't believe that they would show up uninvited.
当巴克斯参议员看到捐款的数目
I don't think senator Baxter is going to mind
应该就不会介意了
when she sees the size of that contribution.
音乐真他妈难听
This music sucks dick.
这叫融合爵士乐
I believe it's jazz fusion.
物理学上  核融合应该要引起爆炸
Yeah, in physics a fusion is supposed to cause a blast.
就像...
Like...
这种！
this!
想跳舞吗？
You want to dance?
我不会跳舞
I don't dance.
现在你会啦
You do now.
谢谢你们的支持
Thanks for your support.
巴克斯参议员吗？
Senator Baxter?
对  我就是
Yes, I am.
我在《出柜》杂志上看过你
Oh, I saw you in "OUT".
我是黛比．瓦特尼
I'm Debbie Novotny.
你好
Hello.
这是我弟弟维克
And this is my brother Vic.
-你好             -你好
- How do you do?  -Hello.
我是迈克的妈妈
I'm Michael's mother.
你知道   我们的女主人
You know, our host.
他的确是个很有魅力的年轻人
Yes, and a very charming young man he is.
我们以前也这麽认为
We used to think so.
天呐  他们围住了参议员
Oh my god, they've cornered the senator.
我们得去救她
We have to save her.
迈克  她是政治人物
She's a politician, Michael.
她有办法为自己解围的
She can talk her way out of anything.
嗨  你好吗？
Hey, how are you doing?
我能帮你弄杯喝的吗？
Can I get you a drink?
想跳舞吗？
Care to dance?
我对皮衣没有兴趣
Huh... I'm not into leather.
我以前也不是啊
Hey, you know, neither was I.
但後来我碰到一个老同学
Then I ran into this old school friend
他把我绑在地下室里 让我当他的性奴
who shackled me in his dungeon and made me his suck-pig.
黑色和蓝色...只适合瘀青
Black and blue, it's... it's fine for bruises, boys,
参加宴会需要穿鲜艳一点的颜色
but when you come to a party, you need a little colour.
你...我的天  谁帮你挑衣服的？
Ha, now, you... Oh my lord, w-who dressed you, honey?
莫蒂西亚．亚当斯吗 （老电影角色）
Morticia Addams? Huh.
来  转过去
Here, turn around.
看  你本来有个很翘的丰臀
See, now you have a fabulous bubble-butt.
但是如果你不露出来的话
But it's not going to do you any good
是没人会发现的
if you don't show it off.
你也是  脱掉外套  让我们看看
You too. Jackets off, let's see those bods.
脱吧
Come on.
快脱  快点  快点
Come on, chop, chop.
这位小姐可是个流浪汉
This lady is a tramp,
而今晚杰克不是唯一幸运的人    （小姐与流浪汉）
and tonight Jack's not the only one getting lucky.
来吧
Come on.
好吧
Oh, man. All right.
好吧  好吧
Ooh, okay, all right, all right.
没事的
All right.
我们给妈咪打电话
We'll call mommy.
喂？
Hello?
嗨  是我
Hi, it's me.
我知道很晚了
I know it's late.
你没事吧？
Is everything all right?
是盖斯  他在闹脾气
It's Gus. He's in one of his moods.
我了解他的脾气
Oh. I remember his moods.
只有你才知道怎麽哄他
Look, you're the one with the magic touch.
可以吗？
Would you mind?
在电话上哄吗？
Over the phone?
我绝望了  什麽都试试吧
I'm desperate. I'll try anything.
听着
Here you go.
-有用吗？         -像魔咒一样
-Did that work?   -Like a charm.
他还是唯一一个欣赏你歌声的人
He's still the only one who appreciates your singing.
什麽？  我声音很好听的
What? I have a lovely voice.
你常常走音
You can barely carry a tune.
-才不是呢           -明明就是
- That's not true.  - Yeah, it is.
其实是的
Yeah, it is.
谢谢帮忙
Listen, thanks for helping.
晚安
'night.
布莱恩
Brian.
别担心  我只是带他参观一下
Don't worry, I'm just giving him a tour
你这...可爱的家
of your... Lovely home.
大卫  非常对不起
David, I'm so sorry.
为什麽？
Why?
我没听见任何人抱怨
I don't hear anyone complaining.
我说  一脚踹在共和党员的蛋蛋上
I say kick those republicans right in the balls.
只是他们连蛋没有而已   (没胆量)
Only they haven't got any.
我的老天！
Oh my god!
妈  能不能别再霸着参议员了？
Ma, could you, um, stop monopolizing the senator?
-戴安  不好意思        -戴安？
- I'm sorry, Diane...  - "Diane"?
迈克  你妈是个了不起的女人
Michael, your mother is a remarkable woman.
大卫  我参加过很多募款活动
You know, David, I attend a lot of fundraisers.
我是说  大家都是出於好意
And I mean, everybody means well,
但我得说  那些活动都非常无聊
but I got to tell you, they're usually very boring things.
可是这个就很有趣  我玩得挺开心
Not this one, I'm having a ball.
妈  我能跟你说句话吗？
Ma, um, can I talk to you for a second?
当然了  亲爱的
Sure, sweetie.
戴安  失陪一下
'scuse me, Diane. Mm-hmm.
小阳光  过来
Hey, sunshine, come here.
跟戴安讲讲你创立的社团
Tell Diane about the club you started.
这是一个非常勇敢的孩子
This is one goddamn brave kid.
我很喜欢他  跟她聊吧
I love him. Talk to her.
你好
How do you do?
把那个端高些
Carry that a little higher.
好了走吧  就这样
There you go, sweetie, that's it.
专业礼仪
Professional courtesy.
你怎麽敢这样对我？还有大卫？
How dare you do this to me? And to David.
我做了什麽？  我只是和戴安聊天而已
Do what? I was just talking to Diane.
你知道她曾经当过服务生吗？
Do you know that she worked as a waitress?
为了照顾她的家人
To take care of her family.
她只是出於礼貌而已
She was just being polite.
礼貌？
Polite?
你真的单纯地认为她想
Do you actually think she wanted to
花一整个晚上跟你一个人聊天吗？
spend her entire evening talking to you?
好吧  又不是我一直死缠着她
Well, it's not as if I nailed her to the floor.
我认为你们都应该离开
I think you should all leave.
我们刚来时 这个宴会死气沉沉
This party was a stinker when we got here.
你应该好好感谢我们才对
You should be thanking us.
感谢你们让我难堪吗？
For embarrassing the hell out of me?
我知道有时候我让人很难接受
You know, I know I'm hard to take. Sometimes.
过分的玩笑  夸张的打扮
Hmm? My jokes, and my appearance,
还有过度热情
and my enthusiasm.
我还知道你有时以我为耻
And I know that sometimes you're ashamed of me.
但是没关系  我是你老妈
And that's okay. I'm your mother,
我可以忍受
And it's part of the deal.
但是  迈克...
But, Michael...
我从没想过 我居然会有以你为耻的一天
I never thought the day would come that I would be ashamed of you.
你什麽意思  这里没卖白桃？
What do you mean, you don't have any white peaches?
喔  这里是匹兹堡
Oh, Pittsburgh.
他甚至负责买菜了
He even does the shopping.
盖斯  看看谁来了  你的精子捐献者
Ah, look who's here Gus, your sperm donor.
你还以为他有工作呢
And you thought he had a job.
这叫「午休时间」
It's called "lunch break". Mm-hmm.
你知道吗  不该把没洗过的东西放进嘴里
You know, you shouldn't put things in your mouth that aren't washed.
你们法国人  真是卫生
You French, so hygienic.
-我愿意冒险             -随便你
-I'll take my chances.  -As you wish.
当然了  你习惯冒险的生活
Of course, you're used to living at risk.
你现在才是在冒险呢
Well, you know, you're taking quite a risk yourself.
事实上  只要有人愿意
In fact, if someone wanted to,
他们随时都可以检举你
they could report you.
是...我会有麻烦
Yes... It would be trouble for me.
我会被遣送回法国
I could be sent back to France.
但是琳赛会更惨
But it'd be far worse for Lindsay.
她会进监狱吧
She could be sent to jail,
那里可不是蔚蓝海岸（旅游圣地）
which is not exactly the Cote d'Azur.
你真的不应该那样做
You know, you really shouldn't do that.
相信我  我也试过劝她
Oh, I tried stopping her, believe me.
但是她不听  你也知道她很善良
But she won't hear of it. You know what a big heart she has.
你觉得这个如何？
What do you think?
是晚饭要吃还是你自己用？
Well, is it for dinner or for you?
-宝贝  来这儿           -不  不行
-Come here, sonny-boy.  -Ah, no-no-no.
我得回家做普罗旺斯炖菜
I have to get home to start my ratatouille.
去你的炖菜 把我的孩子给我
Fuck your ratatouille. Give me my kid,
否则我会用那栉瓜捅你菊花
Or I'll shove that zucchini up your ass.
好  好吧
Okay, okay.
嘿 那是什麽？
Hey, what is it?
只能抱一分钟
Just for a minute
我知道  你说对了  他身上臭臭
I know, you're right. He smells.
多希望我能用相机拍下这罕见的画面
Well, I wish I had a picture to capture this rare moment.
你刚听到什麽了吗？
Did you hear something?
一旦琳赛和我结婚了
You know, once Lindsay and I are married,
我们需要你跟我们保持距离
We'll need you to keep your distance.
为什麽这麽说？
Why is that?
我们要考虑别人的观感
Well, we've got to think about appearances.
我甚至想收养盖斯
I'm even thinking of adopting Gus.
那样的话 一切会圆满而且合法
In that way everything would be nice and legal.
好了  来吧孩子  给我抱抱（法语）
Alors! tu viens ici, mon petit. Tu viens ici, mon petit.
恐同人士闪边去
Homophobia's got to go.
这是怎麽回事？
What's going on here?
我们在抗议圣詹姆斯学院
We're protesting St. James academy's
学生社团政策的不公不义
bigoted policy on student clubs.
泰勒  我已经受够这些了
Taylor, I have had just about enough of this.
这是集会自由  老兄
It's called freedom of assembly, pal.
这里是私人财产  你们现在是非法侵入
This is private property. And you're all trespassing.
我去叫警察
I'm calling the police.
你得留下来听听这个
You might want to stick around for this.
贾斯汀．泰勒想成立一个社团
Justin Taylor tried to organize a club
让不同性倾向的学生
to promote tolerance and understanding
增进对彼此的宽容和理解
between gay and straight students.
他的努力却白费了
His attempt was denied on the basis
因为圣詹姆斯学院自称是私校
that St. James academy is a private institution
而不愿广纳听取学生的意见
and isn't required to acknowledge the voices of all its students.
如果私学还期待得到政府经费的支持
Well, if private schools expect to receive public dollars,
那我们得期待这所学校还给各学子们
then we can expect them to uphold the same values
应有自由和公民权利
of freedom and civil rights
这些正是我国民的基本人权
on which this country is based.
给他们好看  小戴
Give them hell, Di.
我喜欢这照片
I love that picture.
是啊
Yeah.
爸爸和乖儿子
Dada and sonny-boy.
好吧  我是个糟糕的爸爸
Ahh, all right, so I'm a shitty father.
意外吗？
Are we surprised?
我竟然保持着优良的家族传统
I'm upholding a fine family tradition.
你不是一个糟糕的爸爸
You're not a shitty father.
你爱盖斯
You love Gus.
还以为我不会呢  真奇怪
Didn't think I would. It's strange.
奇怪除了自己以外  居然还有你在乎的人？
Knowing there's someone else you care about besides yourself?
给我来一点
Give me some.
你这年纪抽烟已经够糟了
It's bad enough you smoke at your age.
「我这年纪？」
"At my age?"
布莱恩  我是你认识的人之中最成熟的
Brian, I'm the most mature person you know.
你觉得盖斯会先开口说法文吗？
Think Gus is going to speak French before he speaks English?
你怎麽不去睡？
Why don't you go to bed?
琳赛不能自己养大孩子
Well, Lindsay can't raise him on her own.
即使你这麽爱他
And as much as you love him,
你也永远不会成为全职家长
you're never going to be a full-time parent.
如果我想知道新闻  我会看CNN
You know, if I wanted the news, I'd watch CNN.
你无法控制所有人的生活
You can't control everyone's life,
即使你想这麽做
even though you'd like to.
显然如此
Obviously.
你还赖在这儿
You're still here.
对我冷嘲热讽是没用的
Being mean to me has never really worked.
你应该试别的方法
You should try another tactic.
你在干什麽？
What're you doing?
我在用温柔秒杀你
I'm killing you with kindness.
经过证实  这是一个非常有效的方法
It's proven to be a highly effective technique
可以让人达到...自己的目的
for achieving... one's goals.
-他的玩具呢？             -在包包里
- Do you have his toys?  -They're in the bag.
我的钥匙呢？
Where are my keys?
拜托快点  离预约时间只剩20分钟了
Please, please hurry up. The appointment's in 20 minutes.
我知道时间  太好了  在这
I know when the appointment is. Oh, god, here they are.
我的天
Oh,merde.
来的真是时候
It's all we need.
好了  你得弄走他们
Okay, y-you have to get rid of them.
-好吧  让开 让开          -好的
-All right, move, move.   -D'accord.
听着  我们赶时间
I... Look, we're in a hurry.
我发誓我不知道他会带我来这
I-I swear I had no idea he was bringing me over here.
-我们要走了          -他说你出事了
-We have to leave.   -He said you had an accident.
-出事           -这是唯一的方法了
- An accident?  -It was the only way.
能改天再说吗  我们要迟到了
May we save this for some other time?  We're late.
你是不是要出门  皮耶尔？
Are you going somewhere, Pierre?
去领结婚证书  如果你们不介意的话...
To get our marriage license. So, if you'll excuse us...
一会就好
Well, this will just take a minute.
不行不行  我们真的...
Non, non.We really must...
坐下  闭嘴
Sit down and shut up.
-你说什麽？  -坐下
- Excuse me? - Sit down.
好吧
All right.
什麽事？
What is it?
好  现在我不想再听到什麽
Okay, I don't want to hear any more shit
「这是我的错」
about "this is my fault."
「不  这是我的错」
"No, this is my fault."
「都怪我」  「不  都怪我」
"I'm to blame." "No, I'm to blame."
「抱歉」
"I'm sorry."
「不  我才抱歉」之类的屁话
"no, I'm sorry."
但的确是我的错
But it really is my fault.
不  茉儿  是我的错
No, Mel, it was my fault.
全部都是...不不不
All along it was... No, no, no.
是我的错  相信我
It was my fault, trust me.
我做心理治疗的时候想通了
I worked this all out in therapy.
我也是...
And so did I...
我说了闭嘴
I said shut up.
去你的心理治疗
And fuck therapy.
这东西才是关键
This is the only thing that matters.
那是什麽？
What's that?
是我的监护权
It's my parental rights.
我已经签名转让给你
I've signed them over to you.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
布莱恩...
Brian...
你确定吗？
Are you sure?
我不确定的话还会签好吗？
Would I be doing this if I wasn't?
但是为什麽？
But why?
我儿子需要有一对永远在他身边的双亲
Well, my son deserves two parents who'll be there for him
爱着他
and love him.
也彼此相爱
and who love each other.
而让这些事发生的唯一方法
So the only way this deal works
就是你们重修旧好
is if the two of you get back together.
那是什麽  算是贿赂吗？
Well, what is this, some kind of a bribe?
你可以这麽想
You could look at it that way.
或者想成一份慷慨的礼物
Or you can think of it as a very generous gift.
但如果你不想...
But if you don't want it...
你还爱我吗？
Do you still love me?
我从未停止过
I never stopped.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
我同意
Yeah.
好  抢答时间结束
Okay, lightning round's over.
你们的回答是？
Do I hear an answer?
我们同意！
Yes. Yes!
我爱你
I love you.
天啊  你们可是拉拉  坚强点
God, you're dykes for Christ' sake. Toughen up.
我爱你
I love you.
那我怎麽办？
And what about me?
小纪...
Oh, Gui...
对不起
I'm sorry.
说再见  盖斯
Say au revoir, Gus.
黛比  这太棒了！
Oh, Debbie, this is fabulous!
太好了
Oh, good.
对了  罗马诺乾酪！  小阳光
Oh, romano! uh, sunshine,
宝贝  给我们拿点罗马诺乾酪好吗？
Honey, get us some romano, would you, baby?
恐怕那不像我儿子提供的
I'm... I'm afraid it's not as fancy as those little
那些鱼子酱之类的东西那麽高级
caviar things my son was serving...
普通人  和参议员
Well, man, and senators,
都不能只靠鱼子酱过活
cannot live on little caviar things alone.
多谢了
Oh, thanks.
真是太可惜了 迈克不能加入我们
It's too bad, um, Michael couldn't join us.
近来  回他妈妈这里吃义大利面
Well, these days, coming over to his mother's
和喝廉价的酒  不是他的风格
for pasta and vino isn't his style.
我确定他有别的事
I'm sure he had other plans.
对啊  比如和波波吃晚饭
Yeah, like dinner with Bobo.
还有梅丽桑德
And Melisande.
去他的
Well, fuck him.
抱歉  参议员
Oh, sorry, senator.
没关系
Oh, it's okay.
我自己也用那个词
I've used that word myself,
通常在後面加上「小布希」
usually followed by Bush.
我要为此乾杯
I'll drink to that.
让我们一同为乾杯吧
Oh, hell, let's all drink to that.
先让我敬个酒吧
Let me make a toast, please.
首先  敬我们超棒的女主人
First of all, to our wonderful hostess.
-黛比     -谢谢你
- Debbie. - Thank you.
黛比  敬黛比
Debbie! Deb! to Deb.
这杯酒敬你  老姐
Here's to you, sis.
还有庆祝一下小小的胜利
And to little victories.
因为至少  珀金斯博士同意
At least, uh, Dr. Perkins has agreed
把你的请求送到学校董事会了
to take your request to the school board.
多谢了  巴克斯议员
Thanks, senator Baxter.
坐吧
Have a seat.
我不能...我不能留下来
I can't... I can't stay.
你不能？
You can't?
还是你不想？
Or you don't want to?
你吃过了吗？
You eaten?
没有
No.
那就拿个椅子坐
So pull up a chair.
小阳光？
Sunshine?
你能给迈克拿点义大利面吗  宝贝？
Will you get Michael some puttenesca, honey?
你个小混蛋
You little asshole.
对不起  小戴
Sorry, Di.
没关系  那个词我也用过
Oh, it's okay. I've used that one too.
事情都解决了  从此幸福快乐
So it all worked out, happily ever after.
多亏了参议员
Thanks to the senator.
不要自欺欺人
Yeah, don't kid yourself.
那女人在利用你  为了钱和选票
That woman is using you, for money and for votes.
她会继续寻找她下一个目标
She'll move on to her next cause,
他的下一个募款人
her next fund-raiser,
那个时候你算老几？
Then where will you be?
她说这是个小小的胜利
She said it's a small victory.
别以为你已经胜利了
Well, don't think you've won,
那叫做结束
That it's over.
因为以後你只要一不小心
'cause the minute you do that,
你就死定了
You're dead.
不会的   我要有你保护着
Not as long as I've got you to protect me. .
e87efcaa5eee4edaaa1932f5c5d2d640